what's up guys this is Nick at
bobbend.com and today we are bringing
you the best multivitamins for men
whether you're an athlete into
bodybuilding or just looking to meet
your micronutrient intake we're going to
run through a wide variety of
multivitamin products we've got to have
different awards for different
multivitamins like best multivitamins
for bodybuilders the best cheap
multivitamins you're going to learn
about the different ingredients you're
going to find in each multivitamin and
how you can decide which one is right
for your own individual lifestyle
[Music]
now before I go on I should make it
clear that I'm not a medical
professional and this is not medical
advice that's something I have to say if
you're going to start a new supplement
or start anything different in your
health routine make absolutely certain
that you see a healthcare professional
first now I know what you're thinking
why didn't I just tell you the best
multivitamin for men all right I will I
respect your time it's this one it is
huge supplements huge multi we're a
really big fan of this one believe it or
not there are plenty of multi Vitamins
out there that are kind of low in a lot
of vitamins and minerals this one has a
whole 30 different ingredients at a wide
variety of effects not only are you
getting important micronutrients like
vitamin D and choline that are often low
in multivitamins you've also got some
interesting ingredients here outside of
the official list of micronutrients that
might have beneficial effects like
enzymes like CoQ10 like lutein and
lycopene that might help Eye Health
stuff like that very very good before I
go into even more detail on this though
why take a multivitamin is something
that we get a lot here and it's going to
because some research is designed to
question the efficacy of taking
multivitamins sometimes they'll link
multivitamin intake with unhealthy
Lifestyles and unhealthy outcomes the
thing is that's probably because some
people take multivitamins as curals
without actually making any lifestyle
adjustments or eating plenty of fruits
and vegetables as well because the thing
is you do still need to eat your fruits
and vegetables there are over two dozen
vitamins and minerals that we should be
getting every day but fruits and
vegetables they still have plenty of
five booze like multiple types of fiber
that you need that you're not going to
find in multivitamins you've also got
plenty of antioxidants phytonutrients
ingredients like that in fruits and
vegetables so the idea here is a darn
taken multivitamin as a way to skip
having a healthy lifestyle overall it's
like good insurance with your diet it
helps to fill in any gaps it might be
unintentionally creating and it could
also honestly like save you some money
if you don't want to have to go out and
make sure you're getting whole food
sources of absolutely every
micronutrient out there because there
are a lot of them so you can save some
money and also give yourself some peace
of mind with a solid multivitamin so
let's Circle back to why huge multi is
our favorite multivitamin as mentioned
there are actually a lot of
multivitamins out there that don't have
a whole lot of important vitamins and
minerals like the ones that are harder
to get but this one has more than 100 of
the recommended intake of really
important kind of hard to get nutrients
like vitamin D like zinc like vitamin K
all this stuff is important for like
testosterone production bone health all
this kind of stuff this product here in
addition to a really wide variety of
vitamins and minerals it also contains
some interesting additions like lycopene
which is that phytonutrient that's
really popular in tomatoes and
watermelons it has links to heart health
and stuff like that but is it
technically a vitamin or mineral stuff
like lutein really strong links to Eye
Health you'll find it in carrots and
there's even a rare digestive enzyme in
here called bromelain which has some
links to Digestive Health but not
technically a vitamin or mineral so it
takes really nice well-rounded approach
to nutrition and even though it's
multivitamin there's more than just
vitamins and minerals here so that's
what I really like about huge multi we
also named the best multivitamin for
athletes and there's like a lot of
reasons for this as I mentioned earlier
a lot of nutrients that are important
for everyone to get are also important
for athletes to get there's not always
that huge a difference but like for
example vitamin D is really important
for testosterone production there's a
lot of studies linking to that I notice
also testosterone is pretty clearly
important for building muscle in
addition to maintaining bone health as
well plenty of vitamin D in this one and
a lot of multivitamins don't have that
we've also got important antioxidants
like vitamin C and also there's a ginger
extract here and these ingredients can
help to reduce inflammation that can
improve athletic recovery as well the
other thing I wanted to mention here is
the B vitamins there are a lot of B
vitamins in this multi and if you're an
athlete or if you know an athlete
there's a good chance that you have been
around folks taking B vitamin
supplements like dedicated B vitamin
supplements because B vitamins have a
strong link with energy production and
also like focus and mental health as
well now technically you're only really
meant to to say that if you're low in B
vitamins like beneath the recommended
intake you might have problems with
energy production as well as saying
taking a lot of B vitamins will give you
extra energy nonetheless there are
plenty of athletes who do purposely try
to supplement their B vitamins directly
in case taking a bit extra can help with
extra energy production as well right so
B vitamins are very common among
athletes especially among bodybuilders
and there's no harm to taking a little
bit extra so even if you're getting
plenty of them in your daily diet taking
yourself with a lot of B vitamins is a
strategy that a lot of athletes take so
you've got plenty of them here plus
plenty of vitamin D plus plenty of other
ingredients as well we really like this
one for athletes you have you mentioned
that a lot of bodybuilders supplement
with B vitamins earlier that's one of
the reasons why we also picked this as
the best multi-4 bodybuilders number one
all those be vitamins but also in
addition to that there are plenty of
ingredients in here that act as
anti-inflammatory agents which is an
important component of many bodybuilders
regimens so like for example vitamin C
vitamin E these are antioxidants they're
also vitamins but also in addition to
that you've got ingredients like Pine
bark extract which also has links to
anti-inflammatory benefits so a lot of
bodybuilders in addition to making sure
they're getting plenty of calories and
protein and so on they really prioritize
antioxidants and ingredients that might
help with inflammation because that
means that joints might be a bit less
sore and I mean they might recover from
training a little bit more quickly so
you can see there are plenty of like
crossover benefits between bodybuilders
and athletes which is why we made this
the best for both of those categories so
just remember huge supplements huge
multi very good for athletes of all
kinds but also just for anyone looking
to round out their nutrition moving on
from huge if you want to know what the
best multivitamin for the money is like
the best cheap multivitamin but that one
we're going to go with
Wolverine which is one of the best named
multivitamin and supplement companies on
the market just because it is
inexpensive does not mean it is not very
good there's a really wide variety of
ingredients in Wolverines and what's
cool about this is that even though it's
very inexpensive at 20 bucks for the
bottle or 66 cents per day you do still
have a lot of those important
micronutrients that are kind of hard to
get especially for guys right like ones
that are extra important for guys so you
got the ones that are linked with
testosterone including vitamin D and
even Boron which doesn't have a
recommended intake but there is some
interesting research suggesting that
perhaps to a small degree it might help
a testosterone production but it's not a
recommended nutrient so it's usually
left off of these sorts of products but
it is in this one and it's also a good
amount of selenium as well which also
has some interesting hormonal health and
testosterone production again a lot of
multivitamins leave that off their
ingredients list and you get vitamin K
which is becoming increasingly important
in people's intake because more recent
research is suggesting that you don't
just need calcium to keep your bones
strong you also vitamin K to deposited
in the right places in your body so
they've clearly done their research here
there's a wide variety of nutrients here
and they've definitely been looking at
the latest Cutting Edge research on
nutrition as well to make sure you've
got a really nice complete package here
for 66 cents per day let's just pause
this video for a quick second because I
know I'm kind of throwing a lot of
information at you about like benefits
of certain micronutrients and
recommended intakes we have an article
version of this video on our website
there's a lot of information about our
picks and some extra information as well
we didn't cram into this video so you
want to check that out you can just
Google it go to Google write in bar band
best multivitamins for men and it'll
come right up so that's the useful way
to enjoy this information as well so
let's move on to the next pick next up
is the best multivitamin for men over
50. this is a question that we get a lot
and some nutrient needs may change as
you age like there's some research that
suggests that over 50 of guys over 50
are deficient in vitamin B12 for example
so like facts like that are why you want
to make sure you get a multivitamin that
definitely fills in those gaps that are
more likely be pronounced as we get at
all that that one for us was transparent
Labs multivitamin plenty of B12 of
course but there's also plenty of
nutrients here that are important from
energy age especially as a hormonal
Health might be fluctuating a little bit
so if you're concerned about like
healthy hormone production components
like vitamin D and selenium and Boron
those tend to get emphasized a lot for
men over 50. this bug has plenty of them
it's also like some of our other picks
on this list has some ingredients that
aren't technically vitamins or minerals
but may have healthful effects so CoQ10
that's something that may have pretty
profound effects for heart health
there's plenty of that here there's
Boron which may help with testosterone
production at least ever so slightly and
there's also some organic ashwagandha
extract here which is a really
interesting ingredient adaptogens may
help the body to respond to stress more
effectively so when that's a stressful
day at the office or if it's like a
stressful workout ashwagandha may help
like the brain and the body adapt to
that stress so that's a really
interesting part of nutrition research
so it's a really solid product
transparent Labs does a ton of research
the website has citations for all the
research they use to justify everything
they've put into this product and it's
also vegetarian friendly so unlike a lot
of these just have gelatin capsules this
one can be consumed by just about anyone
with dietary restrictions in the realm
of avoiding like meat or dairy or pork
so next I'm going to talk about the best
personalized multivitamin because for
some folks it all feels a little bit
scatter shut like one company will put
out one multivitamin that's just meant
to be useful for absolutely everyone
when actually we all have different
Lifestyles and different diets right so
what care of does it's part of this
interesting new uh sort of wave in the
world of supplementation but you try and
make it more individualized so you go on
their website you fill out a
questionnaire it asks you a bunch of
Staff like how often do you eat fatty
fish do you get much Dairy do you have a
very stressful day job do you exercise
very often you fill out all these sort
of questions and then they send you a
packet with your name on it and with
personalized supplements for the month
so for example me I don't eat very much
Dairy so I get some calcium every day I
don't eat very much fatty fish so I'll
get some Omega-3s So eventually you get
this very personalized approach that
reflects your lifestyle and make sure
you're not paying for supplements that
you don't actually need so I really
really like the approach of care of and
of individualized multivitamins like
that and that's something interesting
definitely check them out we've got a
link in the description below coming up
next what's the best multivitamin for
young men what you want to take a look
at is on it and if you're a young guy
you've probably heard this already this
is a complete package right so you are
taking several pills per day at the
morning and the evening you've got
different Stacks that you're taking
right so are you getting multivitamin in
here of course you are there's a whole
lot of really important key minerals
that they put into this but in addition
to that like in the morning and taking
Alpha Brain which is their very popular
supplement for mental health and focus
you're also getting shroom Tech right so
it's a wide variety of different
mushrooms that can help to improve your
immunity potentially it's also adapt the
ginseness as an adapted gin supplement
in here as mentioned earlier adaptogens
help the body to manage stress it could
be stress from a workout could be stress
from your job in either case this can
help you potentially to endure that sort
of stress there's a really really wide
variety of ways that these products help
to influence your health you've got some
fish oil here but actually comes from
Krill which might have some antioxidants
that's like an angle to omega-3
supplementation that some people like
playing spirulina and chlorella which
really high in antioxidants so again all
these sorts of components that aren't
just vitamins and minerals there's also
always other ways they could influence
your health from omega-3 fatty acids to
adaptogenic compounds and on it they're
a brand you can trust them to have done
their research properly in this area so
it is not very cheap it is a bit under
five bucks per day to take all of these
but there's a kind of confidence you can
get and security from knowing that
you're not just getting micronutrients
in your daily supplements which at the
end of the day are actually just one
piece of the puzzle to overall health
all of that is why we also pick this is
the best all-natural supplement for men
when it comes to micronutrients because
it's not just micronutrients it's a very
natural holistic approach to your health
not just powdered vitamin extracts but
also plenty of plant-based ingredients
plenty of like mushrooms like scoured
from the slopes of Tibet and that sort
of thing plenty of different ways that
different cultures all over the world
have used over the Millennia to improve
their health and it's all been
jam-packed and condensed into the
supplement pack from on it so definitely
that's all natural macro nutrient
supplement as well the only way that I
really take multivitamins or the way
that I like to take them is in gummy
form because like why would you not take
candy if you can take candy and it's
good for you and this is the smarty
pants adult formula this is our pick for
for the best multivitamin gummy the
structure of a multivitamin gummy allows
to have some interesting additions so
for example you can get some fat in here
this has omega-3 fatty acids woven into
the gummy in there and that's something
that you don't really find in other
multivitamins that are just kind of full
of powder inside of capsules right
obviously those those are very healthy
as well but just because of the way the
gummies are made you can get some other
stuff jammed in there so this has
omega-3 fatty acids which is very cool
and interesting and a nice addition to
the nutrient profile but on top of that
you've also got plenty of the Mainstays
you've got vitamin A and D and E all of
which are fat soluble so the extra fat
in that helps a little bit you've also
got plenty of B vitamins and also K
vitamins which as I mentioned earlier
you really want to make sure you're
getting your vitamin K throughout the
day even though I love something that's
done included and it's pretty hard to
get in Whole Foods because vitamin K
helps to deposit calcium in the right
places in the body so it's like less
likely to run up on your arteries more
likely on your bones anyway really good
nutrient profile here the only only real
downside that some people consider
downside is that a seven is six
companies you have to have six companies
every day but personally I haven't had a
pro because I like eating delicious
candy next up we've got a bit of a wild
card in the supplement game the best
greens powder for that we went with
Wolverines greens powder which is also a
reddish powder because it has powdered
up berries in it as well what's a greens
powder well I mentioned a few times in
this video that it's not just vitamins
and minerals that are helpful for the
body right greens powders kind of go all
in on the not vitamins and minerals pod
they do tend to contain vitamins and
minerals and this one actually has a
pretty good spread for greens powder
which is why we included it but the real
thrust Behind the Green spotter industry
is to really try and emphasize the
antioxidants and phytonutrients and
enzymes and those sorts of fibers as
well that are helpful as well that
aren't often found in multivitamins
right so micronutrient wise you are
getting a pretty good spread of B
vitamins in this which again is actually
quite riff or a green spider but they've
also got what is really emphasized these
sorts of products which is a very
healthy dose of organic wheatgrass
spirulina powder and chlorella these are
very very dense with antioxidants and
also there's some interesting research
suggesting that at doses like this
because you're getting like about two
and a half grams of each that could
potentially lead to like reductions in
like waistlines body fat improvements
and metabolic Health that kind of stuff
there's a sort of like correlative
studies but like nonetheless uh the
doses here they are what is reflected in
the literature as ideal doses for these
products like spirulina and chlorella
which are like helpful uh seed plants
like Sea algae that kind of stuff you've
also got some berry juice powders in
this and there's also some enzymes too
which is another thing you often find in
Greens powders so you have both papain
and protease here which have to buy to
more efficiently absorb proteins there's
a really interesting approaches to
Health in products like greens powders a
lot of them are kind of bunk but this
one the research actually does support
and it's transparent as well a lot of
them use proprietary Blends this one
doesn't so Wolverines powder here the
greens and reds powder it's definitely
our favorite greens powder for vitamins
so that does it for our list of the best
men's multivitamins we really want with
this list and this video to empower you
to make the right decisions about your
supplements so when you're going out
there and doing your own research and
making your purchases there are a few
things you want to remember like when
you're buying these sorts of products
right so like number one is the price
like don't just go with the price of the
bottle look at the number of pills per
serving and the pills per day like the
cost per day for all of these products
that's going to really help you break
down like which is actually more
expensive than the others you also look
at the ingredients and the dosing too as
I mentioned earlier all of these
products they actually have different
amounts of each vitamin and mineral and
other ingredients that aren't vitamins
or minerals right so for example vitamin
d and vitamin K calcium I consider like
especially important just based on me
and my own diet and my own lifestyle so
if I see one multivitamin that's a bit
cheaper but it's lower in those
nutrients but it's very high in like
let's say vitamin C and vitamin E then
I'm still going to get the more
expensive ones that's my body actually
needs now you might not you might have
other needs so it's a good idea to take
a bit of an assessment of your diet and
lifestyle and decide which nutrients are
the most important that you get from a
multivitamin and make sure it's actually
in the product another thing to remember
is the ingredients themselves because
it's not always just vitamins and
minerals that people like in their
supplements as mentioned before the
greens powders those tend to be the
go-to for people who really want to
emphasize antioxidants and
phytonutrients and that sort of stuff
which usually are not vitamins minerals
there are also products that have plenty
of enzymes in them there's like the Onyx
one where almost everything here isn't a
vitamin mineral it's something else
that's helpful for the body like
adaptogens and like spirulina and that's
sort of stuff right so there are a lot
of different approaches to not just
multivitamins but like let's say
nutrient supplements you know like
supplements that aren't just about
protein because you've got vitamins
you've got minerals you've got the
adaptogens you've got the enzymes you've
got the probiotics and more so take a
good like audit of your diet what you're
after and uh you'll definitely find a
product here that is going to fill in
the gaps that you need we're really
confident we've done a really good solid
spread of the industry here and whatever
area you want to use to fill in any gaps
in your diet you'll find what you need
right here all right that about does it
for the best multivitamins for men we
think we put together a pretty
comprehensive guide here and there's
definitely something to everyone on this
list if you want to see the full written
article of this video in case you want
to check out some research just go
through this information that you're in
Pace let's head over to Google and write
in bar Ben best multivitamins for men
and it'll pop right up so make sure you
stick around on the channel for more
videos we've got a best Women's
Multivitamin video coming up as well so
keep an eye out for that and uh we're
hoping enjoyed this video
[Music]